本字幕由高清电台整理发布，更多高清电影请访问
https://gaoqing.fm
Yizhao 原创编辑并上传
那些声音都在你的脑子里
肯定很难受吧
It must be very difficult havingall those voices inside one head.
史蒂文·格兰特 马克·斯佩克特 孔苏
Marc Spector. Steven Grant. Khonshu.
还给我 你这个蠢货
Give it back, you fool.
前情提要
你能听见他说话吗？
现在听不见了 我曾经是他的化身
Not anymore.I was his former Avatar.
孔苏惩罚那些已经犯下罪行的人
Khonshu punishes thosewho have already walked an evil path.
他的惩罚来得太晚了
His retribution comes too late.
阿米特是从根源上铲除邪恶
Ammit tears evil up from the root.
真希望你能活着看到我们创造的世界
I wish you could liveto see the world we make.
但是阿米特已经做出了裁决
Yet, Ammit has decided.
你无需怀疑她的审判
You don't need to doubt her judgment.
阿米特会照亮向善的路途
Ammit will light the path to good.
我们必须要让她复活
We must resurrect her.
史蒂文 我和孔苏有约定
Steven, I made a deal with Khonshu.
那个约定的前提是你不能干涉
That deal is contingenton you not interfering.
现在把身体交给我
Now, give me the body.
圣甲虫的作用就是罗盘
That scarab functionsas a kind of compass,
指引我们找到阿米特的墓穴
leading us to Ammit's tomb.
召唤战服
Summon the suit!
不 它去哪了？该死
我们会找到圣甲虫的
We'll find the scarab.
太晚了 哈罗已经得手了
Too late. Harrow has it.
那我们再想其它办法
我们会比他先找到阿米特的墓穴
Then we'll find another way.We'll get to Ammit's tomb first.
然后我就找到了他 还有圣甲虫
And then I found him, with the scarab,
离我们原来的家就20分钟距离
living 20 minutes from our old place.
他在开罗这么乱跑就是送死
Now, he's probably going to get himselfkilled running around Cairo.
这就是你不愿意回家的原因
That's why you look so unhappyto be going home.
可能是焦虑吧
Anxious, maybe.
已经十年了
It's been 10 years.
你就不怕没有回头路了吗？
你偷了那么多古董文物
All those stolen relicsand cheeky antiques?
我没有偷
I don't steal.
那些本来就是赃物
They've already been stolen.
人们总是忽略这一点
That's what people forget.
我把它们从黑市里拿走
I take them off the black market
然后物归原主而已
and return them to their rightful owners.
当然我可能留下几个付生活费
I might keep a few to pay the bills.
你可真机灵
Clever you.
那个天真的小女孩不在了
Not so innocent anymore, eh?
不知道你爸爸看到你现在的样子会怎么想
I wonder what your father would thinkof his little scarab now?
这就永远不得而知了
我觉得他肯定不会让你教我这些
I can't believe he let you teach mehow to do all of this.
他可不是一般的溺爱
你觉得挖掘现场是小孩子该去的地方吗？
You think his dig siteswere any place for a child?
考古学就是一群书呆子搞的烂摊子
Archeology. One big messof obsessive bookworms.
那片沙漠里的过往 就让它随风而去吧
Whatever happened in that desertis lost to the sands.
回忆过去的痛苦太难受了
It's a hard thing,exhuming the pain of the past.
很容易想不开
没完没了地回忆受过的伤害
Fixate on what's hurt us.
好吧 我不会的
Great. Then I won't do either.
说得和真的似的
Like you aren't already.
我也很想念他
I miss him, too, is all.
但是那是你的事 不是我的
But that's your baggage, not mine.
尽量远离过去的困扰吧
也许我想多了…
埃及阿拉伯共和国
但是我就是担心你
旅途愉快 亲爱的
Have a good trip, love.
谢谢
我们找到阿米特了
We found Ammit.
她在这里
She's here.
我们找到她了
她在这
She's here.
马克·斯佩克特来开罗了
Marc Spector's in Cairo.
他在追踪我们
He's tracking us.
我知道 她在这里
I know. She's here.
该死
你杀了他？
我本来要和那家伙谈谈的
I needed to talk to that guy.
关于挖掘现场的事
About a dig site.
看来我只能问问你了
Guess I'm gonna have totalk to you instead.
你来晚了
-你永远别想找到哈罗
-真的吗？
- You're never gonna find Harrow.- Really?
咱们是要跳舞吗？还是打架？
咱们到底要干什么？
去死吧 美国佬
不 马克
别这么做 马克
Don't do it, Marc.
住手
史蒂文呢？
Where's Steven?
停车
你会说阿拉伯语啊？
那你怎么像个外国人似的？
你要带我去哪？
你说要去机场的
You are said airport.
机场
等等 停车 快点停车
Wait, wait, wait. Stop! Stop!Stop, stop! Stop, stop, stop!
我有话和你说
Let me talk to you.
放过我们吧 哥们
Just let us go, man.
刚才不是我 你听我说 就一会儿
我的钱！
我的钱！我的钱呢？
哈罗在哪？
Where's Harrow?
告诉我哈罗在哪
Where is Harrow? Tell me.
马克
马克 够了
Marc, that's enough.
怎么回事？
天啊
Oh, my God.
史蒂文 你干了什么？
Steven, what did you do?
我发誓 不是我干的
I swear. That wasn't me.
那是谁？
Then who was it?
墓穴在哪？
把他带到悬崖边上去
Take him to the ledge.
他只是个孩子
他会老实交代的
He'll talk.
哈罗在哪？
Where is Harrow?
赞美阿米特
我还以为他会老实交代呢
I thought he'd talk.
你是怎么回事 史蒂文？
What the hell's wrong with you, Steven?
我？大开杀戒的可是你
Me? You're the onegoing on a killing spree.
这些不是我干的
I didn't do any of this.
也不是我 听着 要是你不想杀这么多人
Me neither. Listen, if you've gota problem with the body count,
就别再对那个破鸟唯命是从了
I suggest you stop listeningto that stupid pigeon.
少碍事
Stay out of my way.
如果咱们找不到哈罗的挖掘队
Well, if we can't findHarrow's digging crew,
只能换个方法阻止他了
怎么办？其他的神呢？
So? What about the other gods?
有人要释放阿米特 他们就坐视不管吗？
Are they just gonna stand byand allow somebody to unleash Ammit?
召唤众神前来 可能招致他们的狂怒
To signal for an audiencewith the gods is to risk their wrath.
为什么？结果还能有多糟糕？
Why? What's the worst that could happen?
激怒了他们 我可能会被囚禁起来
Anger them enoughand they'll imprison me in stone.
我觉得这倒不是什么坏事
That doesn't sound so bad to me.
真的吗？没有我的治愈盔甲的庇护
See how you fare against Harrow
看你怎么跟哈罗斗
without the protectionof my healing armor.
好吧 那怎么办？
All right. So, what?
你有什么好主意吗？
Do you have any good ideas?
我倒是有个不怎么样的主意
I have a bad one.
孔苏？
Khonshu?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
向众神发出信号 他们别想假装看不见
Sending the godsa signal they can't ignore.
救命
看来你走投无路了 老朋友
You're getting desperate, old bird.
继续挖 无论发生什么都要继续挖
Keep digging!No matter what happens, keep digging!
不要停 我就要被召唤了
Do not stop. I'm about to be called upon.
你不觉得这有点过分了吗？
That was a bit over the top,don't you think?
快点 他们的化身开始集结了
Hurry.They're gathering their Avatars now.
难道他们不是在世界各地吗？
Aren't they scattered all over the world?
是的 但是如果九柱神需要会面
Yes.But for a meeting of the Ennead,
传送门会随时出现
a portal presents itself anywhere.
好吧 那我的传送门在哪里？
Okay. So, where's mine?
上次和众神对话的时候 他们驱逐了我
The last time I spoketo the gods, they banished me.
我们对哈罗的指控必须无懈可击
Our case against Harrowmust be indisputable.
你不一起来吗？
Aren't you coming with?
我会去的
我们进来了
I can't believe it.
天啊 我们进来了
Oh, my days. We're inside.
我们在吉萨大金字塔的里面
We're inside the Great Pyramid of Giza.
孔苏的戏法真是无与伦比
Khonshu's theatrics are unparalleled.
你是他的化身吧
You must be his Avatar.
你好 你是谁？
Hi. And who are you?
我是亚齐尔 哈托尔的化身
哦
音乐和爱的女神？
Goddess of music and love?
厉害
孔苏肯定提过她吧？
他不太喜欢聊众神的事
The gods aren't really his favorite topic.
即便他们是老朋友？
Not even when they are old friends?
抱歉
她说不久之前
孔苏还很喜欢哈托尔的旋律呢
据我所知 孔苏唯一喜欢的旋律
就是痛苦的哀嚎
Well, as far as I know, the only melodyKhonshu enjoys is the sound of pain.
亚齐尔
Yatzil.
孔苏告诉你这里的规矩了吗？
Has Khonshu told you how this works?
没有 有什么我需要注意的吗？
Not really.Is there somethin' I should know?
我尽量遵守规矩
感觉会有些奇怪 但是你会适应的
It's a strange sensation.But you'll get used to it.
好吧
出席者为荷鲁斯 伊西斯 泰芙努特
In attendance, Horus, Isis, Tefnut,
欧西里斯和哈托尔
Osiris and Hathor,
前来聆听孔苏的陈词
to hear the account of Khonshu.
你因为差点暴露我们
已经被放逐过一次了 孔苏
You've been banished oncefor nearly exposing us, Khonshu.
你知道我们鄙视你的媚俗
And you know we despise your garishness,
还有你花里胡哨的面具和武器
your showy masks, and weapons.
但是如果你胆敢再次操控天空
But manipulate the sky again
我们就把你永远囚禁起来
and we will imprison you in stone.
少拿你们自以为是的那一套吓唬我
Spare meyour self-righteous threats!
我被放逐的原因是不放弃人类
I was banishedfor not abandoning humanity,
和你们不一样
unlike the rest of you.
我们没有放弃人类
We have not abandoned humanity.
是人类放弃了我们
They abandoned us.
我们只是让化身去开展我们的目标
We simply trust our Avatarsto carry out our purposes
不给自己招惹无谓的麻烦
without calling undue attentionto ourselves.
和某人不一样
Not like some of us.
化身的力量是有限的
我们需要众神的力量
Avatars are not enough!We need the might of gods.
不要沉溺于虚空之境的富足了
你们的王国快要被颠覆了
Return from the opulence of the Overvoidbefore you lose this realm.
再说最后一次 孔苏…
For the last time, Khonshu...
化身的唯一目的就是观察
The Avatars that remain hereare simply meant to observe.
我们很早以前就决定了 我们不会插手
We decided long agowe did not wish to meddle
人类的事务
in the affairs of man.
我们会作出最合适的决定
We will decide our best course of action.
说出你的目的
Speak your purpose.
我要求审判亚瑟·哈罗
I call for judgment against Arthur Harrow.
罪名是？
The charges?
密谋释放阿米特
Conspiracy to release Ammit!
这可是个严重的指控 孔苏
That is a heavy accusation, Khonshu.
传唤被告
Let us summon the accused.
这不是孔苏化身的临时替代品嘛
So, I see by the presenceof Khonshu's current makeshift Avatar,
这次会议的目的肯定很邪恶
the purposes of our meetingmust be nefarious.
我们为什么在这里你心知肚明
You know exactly why we are here!
我必须得承认我一点都不怀念那个声音
I must admit I do not missthe sound of that voice.
但是我的老主人 说重点吧
But speak, old master, to the point.
你是不是试图从墓穴中释放阿米特？
Do you not seek to release Ammitfrom her tomb?
我在沙漠里
I was in the desert.
如果看沙子都是犯罪
But if visiting the sands were a crime,
那罪犯的队伍可要比尼罗河还长了
the line of sinnerswould be longer than the Nile.
自从他引诱我服侍他以后
Khonshu has searched for Ammit's tomb
孔苏一直在寻找阿米特的墓穴
since he ensnared me to his service.
他被嫉妒和偏执蒙蔽了双眼 他…
His vision is obscuredby jealousy, paranoia, and his...
他是个骗子
He is a deceiver!
你们不能听信这个有污点的神
Do not trust the word of a shamed god.
孔苏的精神错乱了
No, Khonshu is unhinged
他的仆人也不正常
and his servant unwell.
你是什么意思？
How do you mean?
这个人连他自己的名字都不知道
他的结婚证上的名字是马克·斯佩克特
骗子
工作记录上的名字是史蒂夫·格兰特
住口
-我还见过他自言自语…
-住口
- I've seen him speak to himself...- Shut up!
自己威胁自己
我不知道他到底有多少种人格
I have no idea how many personalitieshe must possess.
这个人就是个疯子
The man is clearly insane.
我们绝不容忍在这里出现暴力行为
We will not tolerate violencein this Chamber.
我很难过地告诉各位
It brings me no pleasure
这个人现在深陷困境
to tell youthat this is a deeply troubled man.
孔苏在利用他 就和他当时利用我一样
Khonshu is taking advantage of himthe same way that he abused me,
就和他意图利用这个法庭一样
the way he aspires to abuse this court.
趁着为时未晚 赶快采取行动吧
Take action now before it's too late.
我们要和马克·斯佩克特说话
Let us speak to Marc Spector.
你不舒服吗？
Are you unwell?
是 我是不舒服
I am. I am unwell.
我是需要帮助
I need help.
但是这并不能改变事实 这个人是个…
But that doesn't change the factthat this man is...
这里很安全 你可以大胆地告诉我们
你是不是感觉被孔苏利用了
This is a safe space for you to tell usif you feel exploited by Khonshu.
这和我的感觉没关系 我不是被告 他才是
This is not about my feelings!I'm not the one on trial here. He is!
你们听我说 这个人非常危险
This is about how dangerous he isif you would just listen for a second.
他并没有犯下任何罪行
He has committed no offense.
这件事可以结案了
This matter is concluded.
马克？还有其它办法
Marc? There is another way.
-你必须仔细听我说
-好的
- You must listen to me carefully.- Yes. Yes.
阿米特被埋葬在秘密的地方
连众神都不知道在哪
Ammit was buried in secret.The location hidden even from the gods.
阿米特有很多拥趸 我不知道能相信谁
Ammit had many followers.I didn't know who to trust.
但是肯定有人知道些什么
But someone had to know something.
有个人知道 一个名叫森夫的守卫者
One man. A medjay named Senfu.
他的任务就是记录墓穴的位置
He was tasked with recordingthe location of the tomb
以防众神某天改变心意大发慈悲
in case the gods ever changed their mindsand decided to show mercy.
找到森夫的石棺 你就能找到你要的墓穴
Find Senfu's sarcophagusand you'll find your tomb.
好吧 那我该怎么做？
Okay. How am I supposed to do that?
他的石棺被盗了 然后被卖到黑市去了
His sarcophagus was stolenand sold on the black market.
你可以从那里开始
You might want to start there.
我要一个
I'll take one.
很好 一个 先生
Perfect, one, sir.
这可是全世界最好的果汁
Best juice ever in the world.
我在寻找森夫的石棺
I'm looking for Senfu's sarcophagus.
森夫？
Senfu?
我注意到你了
I hope you like attention.
你找对了人 来对了地方 但是你不是埃及人
Right guy, right place.But you're not Egyptian.
莱拉 你在这干什么？你不该来这里的
Layla, what the hell are you doing here?You shouldn't be here.
为什么不行？因为开罗有人不爽我？
我才不在乎呢
Why? Because my name pisses offa few people in Cairo? Who cares?
我担心的可不是当地人
It's not the localsthat I'm worried about.
跟我来 我会帮你找到你要的东西
Come with me.I'll help you find what you need.
所以我们到底来这干什么？有什么计划？
So what exactly are we gonnado here? What's the plan?
被蒙在鼓里的滋味不好受吧？
It's not pleasantbeing left in the dark, is it?
好吧
我知道我匆匆忙忙离开了你
来了开罗 让你不高兴
I get that you're not happy about meleaving so quickly and coming to Cairo.
我理解
I understand.
等等 你就是这么道歉的？
Wait. Is that your apology?
-真好 真不错
-这样今晚才能顺利
- That's good. That's really good.- Just so we can get through tonight,
要不先别管咱们的破事了
maybe let's just give our shita rest for a moment
咱们先制定计划 找到…
and just try to strategizebefore we get to...
-莫加特？
- Mogart's?- Mogart?
你知道 我不是来帮你的
Just so you know,I'm not here to help you.
我是为了我自己 还有那些
哈罗得手以后会送命的人
I'm here for me and for everyone elsewho would die if Harrow succeeds.
-明白
-很好
- Copy that.- Good.
我很抱歉
I am sorry.
不管你能不能接受
For whatever that's worth.
这个叫莫加特的 他真的有那个石棺吗？
So, this Mogart guy.He's really gonna have his sarcophagus?
是的 我打听过了
Yes. I asked around.
莫加特的藏品可是古董圈里常聊的八卦了
Mogart's collection is prime gossipfor those of us who deal in antiquities.
自从…咱们结婚以后
我就没听到过那个声音
I haven't heard that sound since...Since our wedding.
你本来可以告诉我的 知道吗？
你可以告诉我你的感受的
You could've told me. You know?What's it's been like for you.
关于史蒂文的事
About Steven.
不管怎么样 我一直控制得挺好 直到最近
For what it's worth, I had itunder control until very recently.
发生什么了？
没什么
Doesn't matter.
咱们本来可以一起解决的
We could've handled it together.
是的
这不是我的风格 对吗？
That's not really what I do, is it?
我就是个不善言辞的人
Never really been able to justtalk about everything.
不善于说真话？
Anything real?
是的
好吧 我知道
但是这并不意味着我们不该多沟通
But that doesn't meanthat we shouldn't have.
也许吧 但是现在可能有点晚了
Yeah. Maybe.A little too late for that now, though.
好吧 咱们把整个过程梳理一遍
Okay. Let's get our story straight.
这个家伙有很多朋友
This guy's got a lot of friends.
对 还有很多保镖
Yeah, and a lot with guns.
那是什么？
哈罗的人在尾随我们？
Harrow's men keeping tabs?
我不知道 有可能
I don't know. It could be.
走吧
Let's go.
记住 你的名字是鲁菲诺·埃斯特拉达
好
我们刚从马尔代夫度蜜月回来
We just got back from our honeymoonin the Maldives.
还有什么能告诉他们的小细节吗？
That's an interesting little detailto give to them.
我会告诉他们你在礼品店工作
I'd tell them you worked at a gift shop,
但是他们不会相信我的 对吗？
but they'd never believe me, would they?
贝克
莱拉
好久不见
It's been a while.
-见到你真高兴
-是啊
- Good to see you.- Yeah.
-这边请
-谢谢
- Right this way.- Thank you.
他很期待和你见面
He's looking forward to seeing you.
我保证你们两个会很投缘的
After Madripoor I'm sure you twowill have a lot to talk about.
失陪一下
Excuse me for one moment.
莫加特先生很快就来
Mr. Mogart will be with you shortly.
怎么着 这家伙在后院弄个骑马打仗的游戏
So what? This joker just puts onEl-Mermah games
就是为了好玩？
in his backyard, for fun?
不是 这是他接受私人训练的地方
No, he gets private lessons by the bestin his backyard.
厉害
我喜欢那个袍子
莱拉 请进
Layla. Come in.
见到你真高兴
Such a delight to see you.
我也是
最近怎么样？
How have you been?
很好 谢谢你这么快就请我们过来
Good. Thank you for having us overon such short notice.
别这么说 你要是想来随时欢迎
Oh, please. I hope you realizeyou need no excuse to drop by.
这是我丈夫鲁菲诺
This is my husband, Rufino.
-很高兴见到你
-幸会
- Nice to meet you.- Pleasure.
好
Oh. Right.
希望你明白 这对于我而言不仅仅是收藏
I hope you understandthis is more than a collection to me.
保存历史对于我而言是非常严肃的责任
Preserving history is a responsibilityI take very seriously.
一种自我陶醉的自命不凡的使命感 对吗？
A self-appointed responsibilitythat you alone were able to enjoy, no?
我保护文物还是出于慈善的目的吧
Well, I prefer to see itas a philanthropic effort at preservation.
我能问问 为什么对森夫这么感兴趣吗？
Now, if I may ask, why such interestin Senfu in particular?
其实 我们想买的是…
Oh, actually, our purchases are...
抱歉 你不介意的话
我想听听你丈夫的看法
I'm sorry. I'd like to hearfrom your husband, if you don't mind.
我觉得…我还是看看再说吧
I think that... But I thinkI just would love to take a look.
有趣的人
请自便
-太好了
-好 太好了
拜托 趁你还没搞砸 赶紧让史蒂文出来
Please, just let Steven outbefore you blow this.
不可能 好吧 你看见什么了？
Not a chance. All right, what do you see?
葬仪和守夜祷告的经文是一致的
你说什么？
是真货
我只看见了引导死者的文字
But all I'm seeing is literatureto guide the dead.
没提到具体的地点
There's no location indicated.
因为信息需要破解
Because the informationhas to be unlocked.
它被加密了
好吧…
Okay, um...
能稍等我一下吗？我要和史蒂文谈谈…
Will you give me a minute?I gotta talk to Steven...
你去拖住他
Just keep him occupied.
好吧 史蒂文 你想和我谈谈 说吧 怎么着？
All right, Steven, you wanna talk to me?Talk to me. What now?
你说怎么着？把我的身体还给我然后滚蛋
What now? What now is,you give me the body and you piss off.
该死 现在不是说这个的时候
Damn it, there's not time for this.
告诉我你知道什么
Tell me if there's somethingthat you know.
他就是需要自己在里面待一会儿
因为…他…
他在祷告
对不起 你把我关起来 休想让我帮你
Sorry. If you expect my help,it's not gonna be while I'm imprisoned.
你想让我大开杀戒吗？
-行 那就这么着
-好吧
你是个混蛋
You are the worst.
看看木乃伊的裹尸布
好 我要干什么？
Okay. What do I do?
把第一块拿起来 叠在中间那块上面
Take that first pieceand fold it over the middle piece.
-这个？
-对 就是那个
- This one?- Yes, that one.
-这样？
-对
等一下
如果你把那些星星
Now, if you match those stars up
和那边的另一块拼在一起
with the other piece over there,
-应该能拼成一颗星星…
-你在干什么？
- it should make a star...- What are you doing?
马克 不要
Marc! Don't.
该死
你们真的以为我是个白痴吗？
Do you really think I'm an idiot?
-给我跪下
-安东 住手
- Get on your knees.- Anton, stop!
给我跪下
Get on your knees.
好吧
莱拉 我都准备好和你讲和了
Layla, I was so readyto make peace with you.
你不知道 我们在试着拯救生命
You don't understand.We're trying to save many lives.
朋友 看看石棺里面
Hey, pal.Take a look inside the sarcophagus.
里面有个特别厉害的东西
There's somethin' really, really big.
这挺有意思的
Well, that's interesting.
看来感兴趣的不止你我
It appears we have a concernedthird party here.
起来
不管他们和你说什么
Whatever they've told you,
我保证能给你更好的条件
I'm sure I can offer you somethingmuch more tangible.
宝藏都到手了 还折腾什么线索？
Why settle for a cluewhen you can have the treasure?
安东 别听他的 他在阻止我们找到…
闭嘴吧
他会害死无数人的 相信我
He's gonna kill millions, trust me!
你还好意思说让我相信你？
Are you seriously talking about trust?
没有必要自损身份互相指责
Please, there's no need to descendinto violent accusations.
你们之间的共同点比你们想象的多
Each one of you has so much more in commonthan you know.
莱拉
你一直认为距离
you keep thinking that distance
能够治愈父亲被害给你带来的痛苦
will prevent the woundsfrom your father's murder from reopening.
但是你遇到了障碍
But something stands in your way.
你的丈夫没和你说实话
Your husband doesn't tell you the truth.
而马克 你没有告诉她
是因为你知道如果你说了
And Marc, you don't tell herbecause you know that if you do,
她就会像你看待自己一样看待你了
she'll see you exactlyas you see yourself,
一个不值得爱的人
as unworthy of love.
你这个混蛋
You piece of shit.
安东…
关于这些文物的传说
The lore surrounding these relics,
我可以证明都是真的
I offer proof that it's real.
这个石棺不属于任何人
This sarcophagus doesn't belong to anyone.
动手 召唤战服
Do it. Summon the suit.
让他们得到应有的惩罚吧
安东…
你想亲眼看看吗？
Would you like to see for yourself?
是的
我想看
你在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
感受一下我的神力吧
That's just a tasteof the godly power I offer.
他跑了
Hey, he's gone.
他在哪？
-帮我拖延点时间
-没问题
- Buy me some time.- I can do that.
马克 住手！
Marc, stop it! Stop it!
不 马克！
No, Marc!
把身体交给我 马克！
抱歉
你还好吗？
You all right?
行了 好吧 暂停
That's it. All right, time out.
暂停 各位 咱们都冷静一下好吗？
That's it, time out!Guys, let's all calm down, yeah?
咱们都太激动了
We're all worked up.
咱们冷静一下 好好谈谈…
身体交给你了 马克
莱拉
Layla!
-你没事吧？
-没事
-拿到了吗？
-拿到了
- Do you have it?- Yeah.
-咱们得找辆车
-好 快点
- We need a car.- Yeah, come on.
抓紧时间 马克·斯佩克特 抓紧时间
Tick-tock, Marc Spector.Tick-tock.
我真的挺喜欢那件夹克的
I really liked that jacket.
好吧
哈罗刚才在说什么？
What was Harrow talking about?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他说我有权利知道
He said I had a right to know.
我不知道
I have no idea.
我从来没说过我搬家的真正原因
I never told anyone why I really moved.
但是他知道 他看穿了我的内心
I mean, but he knew,he just saw right through me.
他就是想扰乱你的心神
He's just trying to mess with you.
他在试图控制你的想法
You know, he's trying to get in your mind.
不要让他得逞
No, don't let him do that.
他认为他能够看到
You know, he's got this ideathat he can see
人类的真实本性 根本就是胡扯
the true nature of peopleor some baloney like that.
如果真是那样 就不会有一群杀人狂
If that were true, I don't think he'd havea bunch of homicidal maniacs
做他的信徒了 对吗？
as his disciples, would he?
所以他在说谎？他说你和…
So, it's not true?What he said about you and...
绝对不是真的
No, it's not true.
他就是想挑拨离间 别让他干扰你
每一次我对你有新的了解
Every time I learn something newabout you,
我都会想 “就是这样了
我们之间不会再有任何秘密了”
I think, "That's it. There can't possiblybe any secrets left between us."
然后就会有些事情冒出来
让我觉得根本不了解你
And then something else pops up,and it's like I've not known you at all.
对 你确实不了解
Yeah. You haven't.
根本不了解
我看见他们了
I've spotted them.
试试这个
也许吧
Maybe, actually.
-这个？
-好
- This one?- Okay.
不行 还有其它的吗？
我拼不出完整的星座
就是些支离破碎的布片
I'm not getting any whole constellations.It's just little pieces and fragments.
时间来不及了
This is gonna take forever.
马克 咱们需要史蒂文
- Marc, we need Steven.
他懂这些 我真的觉得应该让他试一下
He understands all of this. I really thinkit's worth giving him a shot.
我召唤众神 你召唤那个寄生虫
I summon the gods,you summon the worm.
他不会归还身体的
马克 没时间了 没事的 来吧
Marc, we can't wait.It's okay, just let go.
咱们没时间了
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
好吧 继续 你来吧
All right, go ahead. You're in.
多谢
Cheers, thanks a lot.
好吧
All right. Yeah.
开始了
这个不需要
Don't need that.
那个也不需要
I don't need that.
史蒂文？
埃及人发明了现代的导航
Egyptians invented modern navigation.
沙漠里并没有什么地标
There's not a lot of landmarksin the desert.
所以他们想了个办法
利用太阳和星星导航
So they came up with a wayto get about using the sun and the stars.
真是天才 对吗？
It's bloody genius, isn't it?
对
这是法语
我知道
咱们该怎么办？
So, what do we do with it?
我也不确定 但是如果…
Well, I'm not sure, but if...
等等 稍等一下
Wait, hang on a minute.
你看见了吗？看见那些细小的针孔了吗？
You see that?You see those little pinpricks there?
那是个星座
That's a constellation.
咱们应该可以用三角测量法
把星星转换成坐标吧？
We should be able to triangulatethe stars into coordinates, right?
让我来扫描一下
Let me just scan it.
其实…抱歉 没那么简单
Well, um, actually...Unfortunately, it's not that simple.
-不行 为什么不行？
-是这样 森夫…
- Not working. Why isn't it working?- Yeah, yeah, you see, Senfu...
森夫大概在2000年前标记了墓穴
Senfu marked that tomb,like, 2,000 years ago.
星星的位置随时间流逝而变化
虽然变得不多
And stars drift over time.Not much as far as stars go,
但是差之毫厘 谬以千里
but it could mean the differencebetween us searching miles away
可能和我们要找的位置相去甚远
from where we're supposed to be looking.
除非我们准确地知道那一天天空的样子
So unless we know exactlywhat the sky looked like on that date,
否则我们就完蛋了
we're buggered.
我记得那天的夜晚
I remember that night.
我记得每一个夜晚
I remember every night.
孔苏？
Khonshu?
我可以还原那天的夜空
I can turn back the night sky.
-怎么做？
-要付出代价
- How?- It will come at a cost,
而且只靠我自己不行
and I cannot do it alone.
史蒂文 如果众神囚禁了我
Steven, when the gods imprison me,
告诉马克来救我
tell Marc to free me.
跟着我做
Do what I do.
什么？像这样？
Yeah? Like this?
天啊 这太神奇了
Oh, man! This is mental.
这就是那天的夜晚
This is the night.
太痛苦了
This is surprisingly painful.
可以了
可以了 太好了
It's working. Yes.
好
这是你自找的 孔苏
You brought this upon yourself, Khonshu.
我的力量正在消逝
I can feel my energy leaving me.
天啊 我不知道还能坚持多久
Oh, God, I don't knowhow much longer I can do this.
坐标确定了 北纬29度 东经25度
Coordinates found,29 degrees north, 25 east.
我知道了 北纬29度 东经25度
史蒂文
史蒂文？马克？
Hey, Steven? Marc?
醒醒
Come on. Come on.
你怎么了？
马克？醒醒
Marc? Come on.
关于孔苏 你说得没错
You were right about Khonshu.
最终他让我们别无选择
And in the end, he left us no choice.
现在他被囚禁于此
Now, he's tethered to this place,
和他之前的众神一样
like many before him.
他能听到我们说话吗？
应该可以
We think so, yes.
我能告诉你一个秘密吗？
Can I tell you a secret?
我曾经很享受替你散播痛苦
I enjoyed dealing out pain on your behalf.
这是我背负的最崇高的罪孽
That is the greatest sin I carry.
我很感激你
I am grateful.
要不是你彻底毁掉了我
Had you not broken me so completely,
我可能永远都不会明白治愈的价值
I might never have knownthe value of healing.
我要去做你做不到的事了
I'm going to do what you could not.
事成之后
And when it's finished,
我想让你记住一件事
是你的折磨铸就了我
Your torment forged me.
我的胜利归功于你
根据漫威漫画改编
漫威影业出品
《月光骑士》
如需获取心理健康资源的相关信息
请访问国家精神疾病联盟网站NAMI.org
字幕翻译： 虫二
Can you hear him?
Shit!
Not worried you might'veburned too many bridges?
Hmm. We'll never know.
Ha! The man indulged you.
- Easy to get stuck.
Just avoid your old haunts.
Call me sentimental,but I worry about you.
Thanks.
Oh, shit.
You killed him?
You're too late.
Oh, wow.
Oh. What, are we dancin'? We fightin'?What are we gonna do?
Ow!
Marc.
Stop it.
Stop.
Where are you taking me?
Airport.
- That wasn't me!
Let me talk to you for a second.
Marc.
What?
Oh, God.
Where's the tomb?
He's just a kid.
Where is Harrow?
- Praise Ammit.- No, kid.
Mmm.
we're gonna have to stop 'em another way.
Help!
Oh, I'll be there.
- I'm Yatzil, Avatar of Hathor.- Okay.
Cool.
Surely Khonshu mentioned her?
- Sorry.
She says it was not so long agoKhonshu enjoyed Hathor's melodies.
I try not to fight it.
Great.
This is a man who literally does not knowhis own name.
He has a marriage certificateunder the name Marc Spector...
Liar!
Employment recordsunder the name Steven Grant.
Stop!
Threaten himself.
Oh.
Okay.
What happened?
Yeah.
Yes.
Yeah, I know.
What is it?
Remember, your name is Rufino Estrada.
Right.
Bek.
Layla.
Cool.
I like the robe.
You, too.
- Hmm.- Mmm-hmm.
Funny man.
Feel free.
- Great.- Yeah. Great.
Well, the burial practices are in linewith the Studenwachen texts.
The what?
It's legit.
Uh-huh.
It's coded.
He just needs a couple minutesin there alone,
'cause... Yeah. He is...
He's praying.
Do you want a bloodbath? Huh?
- Fine, have it your way.- All right.
Check the cartonnage.
- Like this?- Yeah.
Wait a second.
Shit!
Okay.
Get up.
Anton. Anton, don't listen to this man.He's trying to stop us from reaching...
Please, stop.
Layla,
Anton...
Give them what they deserve.
Yes.
I do.
Where is he?
- Give me the body, Marc!
Oh! Sorry.
Let's all just, like, chill the F outand talk for a second...
Take the body.Take the body, take the body, Marc.
- You okay?- Yeah.
Ay.
Oh, well.
No, he's just trying to divide us.Don't let him get in your head.
You don't.
Try that.
Uh... No. Anything else?
He won't return the body.
- We don't have time.
Here we go.
Steven?
Yeah.
Et voilà.
Whoa.
It's French.
I know.
- Whoa!
It's working.
Good.
- I got it. 29 degrees north, 25 east.
Steven.
Where are you?
Can he hear us?
I want you to remember one thing.
I owe my victory to you.